What's going on, Lions fans? Drew
Petting here, offensive coordinator. Me
and my family are are getting settled
here in Detroit and just wanted to give
you a little bit of background on who I
am and what I'm about. Fired up to be
here and can't wait to get to work.
When I am not coaching, outside of
spending time with my family, love to
spend time with my wife and two kids. Uh
I love good food. Uh I love to
snowboard. I like to golf uh when the
weather permits that, but pretty active.
Like to get outside, like to work out,
like to do things, you know, in and
around the community. Looking back to
where I was in 2009 as a volunteer
assistant at Harvard to to tell that
person that this was going to happen,
that I would have this opportunity uh
would be a dream. I I don't think at any
point I thought that this would be the
reality. And I can't tell you kind of
how excited I am and how lucky you are
to be in this position. And uh you know,
don't take it for granted and make the
most of it. Yeah, I've been very
fortunate in my coaching career to be
around some unbelievable coaches,
mentors, uh people that helped grow me,
invested in me both as a coach and as a
person. most recently Kevin Sfansky and
Jonathan Ganon. Worked with both those
guys for almost nine years. Uh Gary
Kubak, Norv Turner, Pat Shurmer, just to
name a few. You know, guys that have
have done it at the highest level as
coordinators, play callers, and head
coaches. Gave me such a great
perspective into the NFL and what it
took to be successful. I think one of
the things you try to do as a coach is
you are constantly learning. You're
always trying to find new ways to do
things, new ways to communicate, new
ways to teach, new ways to attack a
defense. But that's something that's a
process that's never going to be
complete. So, I was going to go to
dinner with three sports figures. Let's
keep it in the NFL. Uh, my favorite
player growing up was Thurman Thomas. My
both my parents are from upstate New
York, so we grew up pretty big Bills
fans, and they, you know, obviously had
some great teams. So, Thurman Thomas
would be at dinner. Growing up in
Boston, probably Tom Brady.
Although, you know what? I'm going to go
Bill Bichc over Tom Brady. Not that I'm
saying one had more impact on the
success than the other because I don't
want to get into that debate. Uh, but as
a coach, there'd probably be a little
bit more knowledge I could gain at that
dinner from him. My third, John Madden.
Played that video game a lot growing up
for many years. So, want him at the
table and want to pick his brain on kind
of the entire process. He saw it from
just about every angle.
>> I think he's going to fit in really like
a glove. To be a really good
coordinator, I think you have to know
all of it. You have to know the run
game, you have to know protections, and
certainly the pass game. Drew, he checks
every one of those boxes, man. It was
about somebody being detailed, have
knowledge of it, man. Uh, enthusiastic,
good communicator, all of those things.
So, before I even brought Drew in, every
time we had crossover tape, I loved
watching his offense. I just thought he
was pretty creative. I thought the the
run game had a lot of versatility. The
play pass, they found ways to move the
football. Guy's very calm. He's very
confident, and he just he fits us.
defenses.
>> I think one of the things that's so
exciting about being here in Detroit in
this organization is, you know, the
history, the culture, the fan base, and
just how much it means to the city and
just seeing how much it meant to
everybody, how they went about their
business, you know, from ownership on
down. I think it's just such an
unbelievable organization to be a part
of. And then obviously, you know, one of
the things that gets makes this job
exciting is the players and to be able
to come into this roster and this
opportunity to coach these guys and work
with these guys knowing the talents are
there, knowing that that there's some
work to be done. uh just extremely
excited uh on so many different levels.
I think Ford Field and the atmosphere on
game day is probably if if not the best,
it's right there. You know, having come
I played here twice on Thanksgiving. Uh
played here six straight years and I
feel like I've played here. I actually
played Buffalo here, uh which is kind of
crazy. Not a lot of people could say
that. Um but I do I think what makes the
atmosphere so special is the fans. I
think the passion that they pour into
the game and the team and the
organization makes it a special place to
coach, a special place to play and and
just thrilled to be a part of it. It it
seems like a really special place with a
lot of great people and and to me that's
what this business is about.